Aku Alatao

Database Administrator

A highly skilled and experienced Database Administrator with over 10 years of experience managing and maintaining PostgreSQL, MySQL, MS SQL Server, Oracle databases. Proficient in database design, installation, configuration, and troubleshooting. Experienced in database optimization, replication, clustering, backup, and recovery. Proficient in database security and access control. Strong analytical and problem-solving skills. Excellent communication and interpersonal skills.



netragonlong@gmail.com
netragonlong.com
netr

SKILLS



WORK EXPERIENCE

Database Administrator CloudNesil

05/2021 - 03/2023 Denizli, Turkey

CloudNesil(https://cloudnesil.com/) is a full-cycle software development company with niche expertise and a focus on the cutting-edge technologies. Achievements/Tasks

- Establish PostgreSQL cluster server to improve performance, resulting in a 30% increase for speed of DML.
- Perform database performance tuning and optimization to improve performance, resulting in a 14% decrease cost from Amazon RDS.
- Develop and implement database optimization strategies to improve performance, resulting in a 10% decrease cost from Amazon RDS.
- Manage and maintain the company's PostgreSQL databases to ensure optimal performance and uptime.
- Monitor PostgreSQL database performance and troubleshoot issues to ensure optimal performance.
- Design and develop database solutions for clients based on their business requirements.

Backend Developer

Digital Contractor

10/2019 - 03/2021 Backend Developer(digitalcontactor.com) is one of the blockchain developing companies found in 2019. Istanbul, Turkey

Achievements/Tasks

- Optimize performance and scalability of backend service by implementing caching, load balancing, and other best practices.
- Migrate the backend code with Python, RUST, PHP, Java and Express.js to develop high-scalable web backend service to improve performance.
- Design the fully optimized databases using PostgreSQL/ MySQL/MongoDB.
- Participate in deploying, automating, maintaining and managing AWS cloud based production system, to ensure the availability, performance, scalability and security of productions systems.
- Identify error and data problem and troubleshoot to solve the problem.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Database Administrator

Cool Digital Solutions

05/2017 - 09/2019 Izmir, Turkey

Cool Digital Solutions(https://letsbecool.com/) is one of those reputable companies that have a strong profile on TechBehemoths.

Achievements/Tasks

- Manage and maintain the company's databases to ensure optimal performance and uptime.
- Monitor database performance and troubleshoot issues to ensure optimal performance.
- Develop and implement backup and recovery strategies to ensure data integrity and availability.
- Perform database tuning and optimization to improve performance, resulting in a 12% decrease cost from Amazon RDS.
- Implement and maintain database security and access control policies.

Database Designer SOFTWARE PEOPLE

10/2015 - 05/2017
SOFTWARE PEOPLE is a Singapore Sole Proprietor. The Business's principal activity is INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY CONSULTANCY.

Achievements/Tasks

- Design and develop database solutions for clients based on their business requirements.
- Create database models and schema designs using industry-standard tools and techniques.
- Develop and implement database optimization strategies to improve performance, resulting in a 16% increase.
- Develop and maintain database documentation and data dictionaries.
- Collaborate with development teams to ensure seamless integration of databases with applications.

Software Programmer

SOFTWARE STUDIO

09/2013 - 10/2015 Singapore

SOFTWARE STUDIO is a Singapore Sole Proprietor, and The Business's principal activity is DEVELOPMENT OF SOFTWARE AND APPLICATIONS.

Achievements/Tasks

- Prepared and reviewed software design documents.
- Developing the Web applications using Python, Java, PHP, HTMLS, CSS3 and client side validations using JavaScript.
- Wrote re-factor and improved existing design and software program codes.
- Extracted, evaluated and migrated information gathered from multiple sources/applications.
- Checked correctness and integrity of data and generate appropriate information/report.
- Worked with databases and data storage technologies PostgreSQL/MySQL/SQLite.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science

Ankara University

04/2008 - 07/2013 Ankara, Turkey

CERTIFICATES

SQL (Advanced) Certificate (07/2023 - Present) https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/6901fbe57eb2

MySQL 5.6 Database Administrator certification (07/2018 - Present)

Singapore